Now, let's say we have a random sample of ten people who each told us how
现在 我们随机抽取十个人，其中每个人都告诉我们
many hours they slept the night before and
他们前一晚睡了多长时间
their temporal memory score on the BBC test. Is
和他们在 BBC 测试中得到的短时记忆分数
there a relationship between these two variables? Well,
这两个变量之间有没有关系？
it's very difficult to judge relationships based on
仅仅靠几个数据列表很难判断是否存在某种关系
just lists of data. So let's visualize it.
所以让我们把它（数据）具象化
This scatter plot visualizes the data in the table.
这个散点图把表格中的数据形象化了
Each point represents one row of the table.
每一个点都代表表格中的一行
Here you can see that the hours slept
在这里你能够看到睡眠时间
was about five and the temporal memory score
是五个小时 而短时记忆分数
looked to be about 55. That must correspond
看起来是55分 那个一定和
to this row here, 56. You can see that hours slept is on the X axis and
这里的这一行 56 一致 你可以看到睡眠时间在 X 轴上而
temporal memory score is on the Y axis. We call the variable on the X axis
短时记忆分数在 y 轴上 我们把 x 轴上的这个变量
the independent variable or the predictor variable. And we call the variable on
叫做自变量或者预测变量 同时我们把 y 轴上的变量
the Y axis the dependent variable, or
叫做因变量
the outcome. We're trying to predict temporal
或者结果 我们尝试用睡眠时间预测
memory score, using hours slept. Now that
短时记忆分数 既然
you've sen this data visualized, what can
你已经完成了这个数据可视化
we say about the relationship between hours
关于睡眠时间和短时记忆之间的关系我们
slept and temporal memory score? This time
能得出什么结论？ 这一次
this question might be easier to answer.
这个问题可能会更容易回答了